

e: m.hariri@gmail.com w: www.mhariri.info



Personal Profile

A passionate software engineer with two decades of experience in product development, technical team leadership and system architecture.

The hallmark of my work is to find key success factors in my teams and projects, and to take initiative and lead in improving those aspects to always end up with a happy customer while spending the least effort.

Work Experience

Engineering Manager at Visualping

October 2022 - Present

Visualping is a seed round ~20 people startup. In my role, I balance both people management and hands-on engineering. I mentor junior engineers by providing clear feedback and engaging in frequent pair-programming sessions. Additionally, I contribute to the product leadership team, helping shape strategy and set priorities for the technology department.

Key achievements during my time at Visualping include:

- Reducing the time required to set up a local development environment from several days to under an hour.
- Leading the initiative to increase our deployment frequency from once a
 week to twice daily, transitioning from a mostly manual process to a
 fully automated one.

Technologies: Typescript, React, NodeJS, AWS(ECS, SQS, RedShift etc), SEO.

Staff Software Engineer at Article

April 2022 - October 2022

Group tech lead for the Warehousing, Transport and Fulfillment Logic business domains. The job includes both strategic and executive aspects. Responsible for coaching tech leads, drive technical alignment and improve interactions b/w product and engineering.

Highlight of my contributions and achievements:

- Coach ~20 developers by pairing, code reviews and feedbacks
- Lead article-in-a-box: run a set of core Article's microservices on a single EC2 to bring accessibility and enable quick experimentation to engineers
- Support Data team in bringing Kafka as a datasource to our data warehouse, enabling visibility into new metrics

Technologies: Java, AWS, ECS, microservices, Kafka, MySQL.

Senior Software Engineer at Spotify

August 2020 - March 2022

Working in customer service business unit, providing customer care agents with the tools to give them all they need to know about an Spotify customer.

We maintain services that handle hundreds of events per second and store terabytes of data and require multi-region active-active deployments.

Technologies: Java, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, microservices.

Senior R&D Engineer at IPsoft

August 2014 - July 2020

The company's vision is to automate all processes in IT infrastructure and business operations, using artificial intelligence, cognitive and autonomic solutions in order to free engineers and technologists to focus on creative endeavors and innovation.

 Build a performance measurement framework for Amelia, leading that from prototype to business value. Resulted in 12x speed up in startup time of one component and 80x speed up in a critical path in Amelia's processing.

Technologies: Java flight recorder, perf, flamegraphs, flamescope, Docker

System Architect at Seamless Distribution AB

July 2013 - July 2014

Developer/Tech Lead at Seamless Distribution AB

July 2009 - July 2013

Designing and managing a financial system for mobile operators with performance requirements as high as 1000+ monetary transactions per second. Most popular technologies in Seamless are Java, MySQL and zookeeper all running under Linux systems.

Co-founder at Parspooyesh

April 2003 - August 2008

Co-founded Parspooyesh company together with two of my friends. The startup grew to more than 20 software developers.

Technologies: Linux, Python, PHP, PostgreSQL

Software Developer at AVAPajoohesh

August 2002 - March 2003

Technologies: MS Visual C++, SQL Server, Java.

Entrepreneurial Activity

2016 - vphone

Place and receive calls on two numbers using one phone. (discontinued)

2014 - Shoppistant

Compare products in the store. www.shoppistant.com

2003 - ParsPooyesh

Creating ISP accounting software. www.parspooyesh.com

Education

KTH (Royal Institute of Technology) University

August 2008 - May 2010

Master's Degree of Software Engineering of Distributed Systems